Ananya Anant

Engineering Student

A dedicated and resourceful engineering student who wants to seek software development positions to utilize my skills for solving real-world problems creatively and effectively along with gain experience, enhancing my skills and learning new technologies.

- Patna, Bihar, India
- ananyaanant1902@gmail.com
- +91 8210200524
- Github: https://github.com/ananyaanant1902
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ananya-anant-173214194/

Experience

O Publicity and Media Head

IET-VIT(2021-2022)

- Lead the chapter with marketing ideas and design implementations.
- Organizes campaigns

Core Committee Member

IET-VIT(2020-2021)

- Actively participated in events and created designs for chapter events.
- Hack-a-Thon 3.0 : Event Co-Ordinator
- Social Transformer : Event Co-Ordinator

Core Commitee Member

HEARTS-VIT(2020-2021)

- Was part of Management team for the NGO
- Organizer of Few Workshops and Competitions.

) Core Commitee Member

5th Pillar-VIT (2020-2021)

- Was part of Management, Content Writing and Design team for the NGO
- Organizer of Few Events and Competitions.
- Wrote few blogs and design some posters.

Product Designer Intern

Canteliver Labs

- Works with UI/UX department of the company for their website
- Also gained experience with the technical side of web development (Front-End)

Projects

IoT Based Industry Protection System

With use of Node-red and Arudino

My part was to create a dashboard for seeing the values and also to send user mail in case of emergency using Node-Red

House Price Prediction System

using XGBRegressor model

Prediction of house price from a given dataset using XGBRegressor model and various other libraries

Education Qualification

Vellore Institute Of Technology, Vellore

B.Tech. in Electrical and Electronics

7.75 (Till Now)

Loyola High School, Patna

2017-2019 Higher Secondary

CBSE-85%

Christ Church Diocesan School, Patna

2004-2017 High School CBSE-9.4 CGPA

Skills

Technical Skills

- Java
- MySQL
- HTML5
- CSS
- Problem Solving
- Python

Softwares

- Intellij IDEA
- Eclipse
- Visual Studio Code
- MySQL
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Adobe XD
- Figma
- Adobe After Effects

Extra Skills

- UI/UX Design
- Graphic Design
- Motion Design
- Front-End Web Development
- Leadership
- Management
- Soft-Skills
- Public Speaking

Courses and Certification

Udemy

- Java Programing: Complete Beginner to Advanced
- MYSQL BootCamp
- UI/UX using Adobe XD

Others

- Coursera: Google UI/UX Course
- Java Basics: HackerRank
- SQL: SOLOLEARN
- Java: Sololearn